# **Christopher A. Bracco**

web designer, developer, etc.

## **Biography**

Hello! My name is Chris and I am a web designer and developer who cares about user-centered design, performance, and accessibility.

Eighteen months after birth I was booting up MS-DOS to play Reader Rabbit, and my first website went live on Angelfire when I was twelve years old.

Today you can find me designing and developing responsive web applications and websites with great user experiences.

#### Education

Bachelor of Science, Management Minor, Music Technology The Pennsylvania State University 2006–2010

Modern Front-End Web Developer Modern Developer Programming Academy 2015–2016

#### **Focus Areas**

Team Leadership · Responsive Design · UI Design · Agile Development · Performance · Accessibility · Rapid Prototyping · Open-Source Software

# Working Knowledge Of...

HTML · CSS · JavaScript · Command Line · Adobe Photoshop, Illustrator · Templating Languages · Task Runners · Package Managers · Version Control · Google Apps, Analytics, Webmaster Tools · Slack, Trello, Basecamp · Microsoft Office, iWork

### **Contact Information**

+1 (201) 953-3928 hello@chrisbracco.com @cbracco

### **Work Experience**

Muck Rack (2016–Present)

Currently I work as a front-end web developer for Muck Rack, a web application that helps connect journalists, publications, and PR folks. I work with the product team on planning and implementing new application features using UX best practices, as well as doing routine maintenance, refactoring, and bug fixes.

Big Room Studios (2012–2015)

A small-to-medium-sized creative technology company where I helped plan and execute responsive web applications for clients such as Target, Wireless Zone, NextWorth, Portland Pirates, and more. I also lead the company-wide shift of internal processes to focus on content-first, responsive development strategies.

### Dispatch Magazine (2010–2012)

I moved to Portland, Maine to help launch a brand new magazine focused on the local music and film scenes in Maine. I was the lead web developer who helped design the early branding materials and built the first iterations of the web version of the magazine using the WordPress content management system.

Open-Source Software (2012—Present)
I try to make contributions to open-source software in my free time, as a way to give back to the community that continues to provide me with the resources necessary to be a better designer and developer.

Freelance Web Development (2006—Present)

Over the past decade (and counting) I have worked on several freelance web design, branding, and development projects. These include solo projects, startups, contracting out my services to other web development agencies, and more.